As feudal Japan enjoys peace,
the samurai era is waning.
But this fragile calm is threatened
by the growing power of Lord Naritsugu,
the Shogun's sadistic younger brother.
Sir Doi realizes
Naritsugu will ruin the Shogunate
if he gains higher political standing.
As Naritsugu's evil deeds
are quickly hushed up, Sir Doi must act.
March 5, 1844 - Akashi CIan House EIder
zusho Mamiya commits harakiri.
Mamiya's harakiri to the Shogun
was against Lord Naritsugu.
Lord Naritsugu was born
with a vicious nature.
His lust for flesh and dishonorable
conduct cannot be pardoned.
What should we do?
Man: Shogun Council Elders,
Sir Doi has returned.
The Shogun orders us to settle
the matter of his half-brother quietly.
SIR DOI
Top Shogun official
We blame those that named Naritsugu
an adopted Akashi son.
This dilemma drove Mamiya
to harakiri.
- His appeal to us for action...
- l'm aware of that!
But we must respect
the Shogun's rule.
His justice is noble
by heaven's will.
Arguing is pointless!
13 ASSASSlNS
Shinzaemon Shimada,
l presume?
ln the flesh.
You're a hard man to find.
Sir Doi.
Sorry for the late hour.
l've been a widower for years,
with few family obligations.
SHINZAEMON
Shogun Samurai
Perhaps you've heard
about the outrage.
l have.
So...
what do you
make of Lord Naritsugu?
Forgive my frankness...
he is no worthy heir
to the noble Akashi clan.
With the Shogun's consent,
l suggest Naritsugu steps down.
A more suitable heir is needed.
The Shogun will not grant it.
Why not?
He has appointed Naritsugu
as his senior advisor,
effective on Naritsugu's
next visit to Edo.
The Shogun will allow that boy
to meddle in political affairs?
lncidentally,
l invited someone here.
Speak with him.
l'm Yukie Makino,
a subject of the Lord of Owari.
l serve the Agematsu in Kiso.
l'm Shinzaemon Shimada.
Kiso?
l heard about an incident last year
between the Akashi and Owari clans.
Rumors of a scandal...
l'll tell you all.
l'll keep no secrets.
Makino:
In April of last year...
Lord Naritsugu
of the Akashi cIan...
stayed overnight at Kiso.
He is the son
of the former Shogun.
LORD NARlTSUGU
Akashi Clan ruler
Nobility must be properly served.
Our wives and daughters were
brought in for his full hospitality.
Uneme.
Father.
- ls his feast in order?
- Yes.
And the picture scrolls
for his entertainment?
l'll fetch them.
Have your wife
get them instead.
Chise.
Makino: My son had married Chise
onIy two months prior.
I ordered her
to do this petty task.
And I'll regret it to my grave.
Naritsugu:
Who might you be?
l belong
to the Uneme Makino family.
My Lord, please release me.
Chise!
Chise?
Chise?!
- Chise?
Naritsugu: Kiso women
are such mountain monkeys.
They defy me by scratching.
Are you a monkey too, servant?
Chise.
Uneme:
Chise!
Monkey necks can be so tough.
Makino:
That same night...
Chise slit her throat in disgrace.
Makino:
My son and his new bride slain...
before my very eyes.
This is torture.
Rather than living in disgrace
l ponder harakiri.
But l can't... l remember the shame
my Lord Owari has endured.
Mock me for grumbling.
l continue my worthless life
solely to remain a living witness
to this tragedy.
Sir Doi: As the Council Elder
enacting the Shogun's justice...
some things l can do,
others l cannot.
lf l turn my back on the Shogun
and find fault with his lineage,
then his rule will spiral into chaos
and destroy years of peace.
As the Shogun's senior advisor,
l cannot do it.
Are you asking
if l can do something?
Since Mamiya's harakiri protest
three days ago...
l've searched my soul
for a solution.
l have decided it's you.
Who's the woman?
Sir Doi: Akashi land
was once most fertiIe.
But Naritsugu's
reIentIess Iand taxes
made starving peasants
hunger for revolt.
This woman...
is the daughter
of the peasant leader.
Sir Doi:
He did this.
He cut off her Iimbs.
And brought her to Edo
as his plaything.
But he grew bored with her
and cast her out.
ls there no mercy?
Shinzaemon, l need not mention
my honor and position.
lf this continues, chaos will ruin
our nation and the people will suffer.
Poor woman...
what of your family's fate?
He cut out her tongue as well.
Shinzaemon's voice:
"TotaI massacre."
How fate smiles on me.
As a samurai
in this era of peace...
l've been wishing
for a noble death.
Now fate has called me here.
See, my hands won't stop
trembling.
Hmm...
lt's a warrior's battle shakes.
l will accomplish your wish...
with magnificence.
Sir Hanbei,
thank you for coming.
HANBEI
Naritsugu's Chief Samurai
- Asakawa, where's Lord Naritsugu?
- ln the banquet hall.
( dull thump,
woman screams )
The Mamiya?
l told you not to trouble
the Mamiya family!
Asakawa: l can't disobey
Lord Naritsugu's orders.
Tsk.
My Lord!
Yes, Hanbei?
Sir Doi has humbly requested
that you leave the Mamiya family alone.
Governmental orders!
Doi again!
That grumbling Shogun advisor.
Lord Naritsugu!
Naritsugu:
What makes a samurai warrior?
You men mindlessly chant
"loyalty, duty"...
like a Buddhist prayer.
But if servants are spoiled,
then one day, they forget
their duty to serve.
Servants like Mamiya make light
of their master and revolt.
Punishing one's servants,
who are certified as property
by the Shogun...
punishment is a master's duty.
Dying for one's master
is the way of the samurai.
Dying for one's husband
is the way of women.
( woman groans,
bowstring creaks )
We must protect these ways,
right, Hanbei?
Yes.
Hanbei: They won't let him
get away with it.
Things worked out too easiIy
for our Lord, don't you think?
Asakawa:
He was given special treatment.
Though born of a different mother,
he is still the Shogun's brother.
Hanbei:
So how will Sir Doi save face?
As the man in charge
of the nation's justice...
he must deIiver a verdict to save
his honor in a scandaI Iike this.
So, Sir Doi is plotting something?
Who goes there?
Attendant Deguchi at your service.
Hanbei:
Gather men and spy on Sir Doi.
Bribe the gatekeepers and servants.
Get his list of visitors
since Mamiya's harakiri.
We protect our Lord at all costs.
Such is our duty.
Yukie Makino of the Owari clan?
Owari?
Makino?
Makino was present
during our Kiso visit.
Hanbei:
So Makino met with Shinzaemon.
Asakawa:
Do you know this Shinzaemon?
We attended the same school, even
trained in the sword at the same dojo.
We were competitive classmates.
ls he that skilled?
He's not as shrewd, not as strong.
But he never gives up.
Backed into a corner, he won't budge.
Won't overplay his hand.
He's a man who beats you
in the end.
lf Doi has picked him...
then we've drawn the worst luck.
Shinzaemon:
lmpressive as always, Hirayama.
l'm sorry for always borrowing
your dojo without permission.
You honor me by using it.
Your spirit keeps the dojo alive.
A match for old time's sake?
Hirayama: Better to save our energy
for bigger tasks, right?
There are no big or small tasks.
All are equally important.
You follow me?
Guess you still lack training.
Since your teaching, l have been
on the path of the sword for 10 years.
As the months
and seasons changed...
l lived on the money you gave me
as a sword for hire...
knowing that, one day,
l'd surrender my life to you.
l thought a time would come
when l could repay you.
Yet l have no choice
but to regret...
l have not been
able to repay you yet, master.
Shinzaemon:
Your appreciation.
My small contribution
means so much?
l thank you.
Man: What a rare samurai
in these times!
Shinzaemon:
Oh, Kuranaga!
l'm Hirayama.
Kuranaga:
We can't waste his spirit.
Have him join us.
Shinzaemon:
Hmm.
l chose five of my men.
They await you inside.
Kuranaga: Mitsuhashi,
get acquainted with Hirayama.
l am Mitsuhashi,
at your service.
Kuranaga: l present my subordinates,
Otake and Hioki.
Mitsuhashi:
And my men, Higuchi and Horii.
Hand-picked from hundreds.
Kuranaga:
We are still few.
It's hard to find skiIIed samurai
in this day and age.
Others are samurai of IittIe worth.
Our five lives are in your hands,
Sir Shinzaemon.
l see.
Then listen up.
By private order of Sir Doi...
we've been assigned to take the life
of Lord Naritsugu of the Akashi clan.
Next month, Naritsugu will leave Edo
for the Akashi domain.
lf he enters Akashi land,
we can't touch him.
Hirayama:
So we strike en route?
That's the plan. lt's absurd
with so little time and few men.
But these days, how many samurai
use their swords in actual battle?
Not them, not us.
A real challenge.
He who values his life
dies a dog's death.
You've entrusted me
with your lives.
l'll spend them...
at my discretion.
Shinzaemon's voice:
Now, we are nine.
How many other
true samurai are Ieft?
Hioki:
l'll take my leave.
Man:
What was that meeting?
Hioki:
Akashi samurai?
Man:
Now you know!
How dare you point your sword
at us, novice!
Who are you?
State your name.
Hirayama. l'm a ronin.
He killed our sword masters
in one slice.
l won't permit
such blatant moves again.
lf Sir Doi so wishes,
the coals we once cooled...
will ignite into a blaze
burning down our clan!
Forgive me
for my thoughtless act.
Now it's clear.
lt is Shinzaemon.
Man:
Place your bets.
Gambler:
Odd or even.
Odd.
Lady Luck is with you.
Don't talk to me.
What?
Luck leaves
when unlucky men talk.
Shogun retainer Shimada's
third son.
Samurai are always asking
to borrow money.
My shop is full
of pawned swords.
These days, swords are
only good for cutting radishes.
Whoa!
Man:
Well, hello Uncle!
Womanizing at your age
is bad form, don't you think?
Bravo Nephew!
You young rogue.
Sake bought with gambling money
tastes best.
Spare me the irony.
Gambling is the only time
l feel alive.
Samurai status
doesn't suit me.
l too hated being a samurai,
but then l realized...
l could never be a true player
by playing around.
A true player
doesn't try so hard.
l'm not trying too hard.
l wonder.
How's your girl?
Well...
she hasn't kicked me out yet.
Be yourself.
But don't overdo it!
Lords are making
their annual trips home.
Shouldn't you be busy?
Work is my excuse
to gamble too.
l'm on a mission,
a long shot.
Will that gamble pay off?
Pay off? lt's like walking
through the eye of a needle.
Quit while you're ahead.
You're clever.
But your uncle is a born fool.
l go for broke and bet it all.
And if you win?
lf, by chance, l win...
in time, someone
might appreciate me.
Maybe.
Betting on yourself is true gambling.
Who's overdoing it now?
l'll say this, Shinrokuro.
My gamble is more exciting than yours,
with the same odds.
Woman:
Shinrokuro, are you home?
You tease.
lf you're here, say so.
Shinrokuro:
I'm neither here nor there.
No teasing. You're right here.
Shinrokuro:
I saw my uncle.
Sir Shinzaemon?
Yes.
What's wrong?
Did something happen?
Tsuya...
No.
Don't.
Shinrokuro.
l'll be gone for a while.
When will you return?
Soon.
But if l'm late...
l'll be at the Festival
of the Dead.
Burn the honorary torch
and wait.
This is my one and only pupil.
Ogura at your service.
Shinzaemon:
Are your parents still alive?
Father died two years ago;
Mother passed when l was five.
l come from a lowly family
serving a noble's concubine.
Since deciding to live for the sword,
l've waited for this day...
to use my skills for society.
Allow me to join you.
Hirayama:
l request that you take him too.
But he's too young.
Shinzaemon, you're wrong.
Devotion knows no age.
A samurai's life isn't measured
in length, is it?
My logic was shallow.
May we ask your help?
Thank you very much!
l will surrender my life
to serve you.
And who might you be?
Sahara, a lowly ronin...
with no redeeming merit
but my spear.
- Hirayama: l vouch only for his skill.
Hirayama told me
of your mission.
Fighting a larger enemy is admirable.
l very much want to join but...
one small request.
Shinzaemon:
Which is?
Pay me 200 ryo up front.
Kuranaga:
You're only joining for the money?
Let me be clear. My sympathy with your
cause has nothing to do with money.
With no relationship or debts to you,
do you expect me to work for free?
How will you use the money?
The first 120 ryo for lifelong debts,
plus something nice for my relatives.
Thirty ryo for a tomb for my wife,
who died from my hardships.
Twenty for my preparations
as well.
And the rest?
To experience the "luxuries"
l never had in this life.
My kind of man.
His spirit is a bargain at 200.
Now, we're 1 1 .
Our quality outshines
our quantity.
Shinrokuro is here.
l'll take the odds
on your big gamble.
What do you wager?
lf it's a true gamble,
there's only one thing l can bet.
lf you refuse,
start by killing me now.
And now, we're 12!
No mercy! There's no samurai code
or fair play in battle!
No sword? Use a stick.
No stick? Use a rock.
No rock?
Use your fists and feet!
Lose your life,
but make the enemy pay!
Shinzaemon:
Horii.
Higuchi.
Train in explosives.
Sahara's voice:
Rest in peace.
I'll join you shortly.
Shinzaemon: Hurry up
with the preparations. We depart soon.
Lord Naritsugu
departs tomorrow.
Kuranaga:
Finally, he makes a move.
So where's
our best point of attack?
How about the Toda
boat crossing?
They'll send
half their men first.
The others will stand guard
as Naritsugu crosses.
Their troops split...
better to attack then.
No, they'll be on full alert.
Won't make any wrong moves.
Let's keep them anxious and running,
never knowing where we'll strike.
Hmm...
That's a good point to consider.
Hanbei:
Shinza? You here?
lt's Hanbei Kito
of the Akashi clan.
Shinza!
Hanbei.
l knew you'd come.
Glad to see you.
Hanbei:
I thought you had left already.
lf we had time,
l'd enjoy a match of go.
l still lead in wins.
Leave our score aside
until we meet again.
Again?
For years l envied you: a man from
a good family, close to the Shogun...
appointed to his elite guards.
After you moved up,
l commanded the same post.
To catch up,
l joined Lord Naritsugu.
He earned a fortune
when he was adopted by the Akashi.
That led me into this situation.
What an ill twist of fate.
Shinzaemon:
Perhaps we both embraced fate.
A samurai leads a helpless life.
Hanbei: Mamiya should've committed
harakiri in front of his Lord.
l once had that intention...
but l could not betray his father,
the former Shogun.
l lost my chance to move ahead.
l regret not beating you.
l was unable to commit harakiri.
As a samurai, l'll do
what must be done for the people.
For the people?
A samurai must do but one thing.
Serve his master, correct?
What an ill twist of fate.
lt's a long road
to the Akashi domain.
See you there.
Bet on it.
Edo
Shinrokuro's voice:
Uncle, three days have passed
since Naritsugu left Edo.
Where do we make our stand?
Hanbei's voice:
How wiII Shinza make his move?
We kept you waiting.
The verdict is out.
Brothers, we take Lord Naritsugu at...
Ochiai in the Mino province.
Ochiai
Naritsugu offended the Owari
by killing Makino's son in Kiso.
We can enlist Makino's help at Kiso.
Ask him to sign a non-transit act
using Lord Owari's name...
to ban Naritsugu from passing.
He'll join us due to the murder
of his son and daughter-in-law.
And then?
Shinzaemon:
Only two possible routes.
The Kiso Pass
or the Kamizaka Pass.
Either way,
he must pass via Ochiai.
We'll fortify Ochiai
and strike hard.
What if they forgo appearances
and don't pay respect to the Naegi clan?
There's a chance they may not stop.
Shinzaemon:
But l wager they will.
Shinzaemon: With 12 men
challenging a bigger enemy...
no matter how much we plan,
we must have faith in luck.
We pick here and risk it all.
With heaven's will,
the dice say Ochiai.
Risk it all!
Kuranaga, you're best suited
to get Makino's assistance.
Leave it to me.
l'll get that road blocked.
- Take lshizuka with you.
- l'm grateful.
- Let's get moving.
Excuse us.
Shinzaemon:
Mitsuhashi, ready the horses.
Ready and waiting, sir.
Shinzaemon: Go on ahead and negotiate
with the Mayor of Ochiai.
Give him these orders
from Sir Doi.
Understood.
How should l proceed?
Buy them all out.
Yes, sir.
- Shinzaemon: Let's ride!
Fast and hard
to pass the enemy!
You Shinzaemon Shimada?
ln the flesh.
Are you Akashi henchmen?
Don't follow them!
Anyone hurt?
That Hanbei,
he drew first blood.
Probably put coins in the hands
of these broke ronin.
Not a real attack.
His aim was to break our strength.
First time you killed as well?
l've fenced with real blades
many times but...
killing a man is a first.
There's only one road,
but we don't know where they'll strike.
lf they attack harder next time,
we could get hurt.
Let's accept
Hanbei's welcome.
And we'll vanish as well.
Huh?
Hioki's got
some new friends!
- Hioki: Disgusting!
Sahara: We'll travel northwest along
the ridge and cut through the valley,
over the mountain to Owari territory.
l had strict monastic training
when l was young in the mountains.
The mountain brings blessings
but its true nature is fear itself.
l see.
We are nobodies.
Huh?
He's right. No titles,
no affiliations. Nobodies.
A buyout?
Mitsuhashi:
That is our wish.
l won't go against
Sir Doi's orders.
But convincing the town
will be hard.
What?
Our deposit. Not enough?
Sahara:
The forest grows thicker.
Shinzaemon:
Hirayama, we're lost.
Sahara: Perhaps we should have
detoured at that cliff?
- Hirayama: That can't be.
- Sahara: But...
Who are you?
A bandit?
Or a raccoon goblin?
Do l look like a raccoon?
Ouch!
Couldn't lower me down, idiot!?
At least thank me.
You from these parts?
- Do l look so?
- Hirayama: lnsolent!
Ah-hh!
l ain't no ghost or bandit.
l hunt beasts
from mountain to mountain.
Any men with you?
Gone. 'Cause l laid
my hands on Upashi.
Upashi?
The boss's woman.
So he punished you.
Fools are the same wherever you go.
Hold your tongue!
- Got a name, son?
Koyata Kiga.
My ancestors were defeated warriors,
legitimate samurai stock.
What's so funny?
The name's Shinzaemon.
And these are my men.
What are samurai
doing out here?
A shortcut
made us lose our way.
l'll be your guide,
if you got food.
Deal?
- What's that?
Don't like bugs?
Watch.
Don't be a little girl!
What?
Let's go.
What now?
Hmm?
Leave the rabbit.
We have important
work to do.
More important
than roast rabbit?
Sir Hanbei!
What is it?
Emergency.
Lord Naritsugu's passage
is banned.
Hanbei:
His passage is banned?
What's the matter?
You fools, will you stand idly by
at this humiliation?
Lord Owari is
from the top three clans.
But l am the son
of the former Shogun
and brother
to the current Shogun.
Cross over!
Hanbei:
Watch and learn.
We must go through Owari land.
Can our Lord swallow his pride?
Let's see if he gets his way
as he usuaIIy does.
Naritsugu:
Who are you?
ldentify yourself.
Out of my way...
or l'll kill you without mercy.
Last April...
in Kiso, you killed my son...
Uneme Makino and his wife.
l am Yukie Makino.
Does daddy monkey
have hard bones too?
My Lord!
Hanbei?
Leave this.
Let's go back.
Hanbei:
Owari only banned Lord Naritsugu.
His entourage can enter.
They are Akashi members.
l see.
The rest will guard our Lord.
lf people hear Owari blocked us...
if we don't visit the Naegi,
our Lord will be ridiculed.
Let them laugh.
Within a year, our Lord
will be second-in-command.
You risk his life and the Akashi clan
by visiting the Naegi.
You seem most afraid
of Shinzaemon.
What can that weak
Shogun servant do?
Since paying off the ronin,
there's no sign of him.
Perhaps he fears our clan
and ran?
Don't you see? He's the one
who blocked our passage.
Naritsugu: Do you cling to your life so
as to make me a laughing stock?
Hanbei: Desperate times
call for desperate measures.
l hear any samurai would choose death
over making his Lord a laughing stock.
Choose the foolish path.
lt's more fun that way.
Naritsugu:
Let's go, Hanbei.
- Hanbei: Move out!
We've had enough.
Koyata:
Hmm?
- Huh?
Oh, the road.
The road!
- Kuranaga: Welcome. Been expecting you.
- Shinzaemon: You've prepared well.
Progress couldn't be better.
Shinzaemon:
Did it work?
Makino stopped them perfectly.
Naritsugu diverted his troops.
Shinzaemon:
Well, well.
Our long shot paid off.
Shinzaemon:
How many men with Naritsugu?
Kuranaga:
Seventy men.
Shinzaemon:
And Makino?
Kuranaga: He left nothing to chance.
He chose the path of harakiri.
He took full blame,
left no evidence behind.
He's a mighty samurai.
We must achieve
our mission for him.
Hey!
Got dinner!
Who is he?
He dropped in
when we entered the forest.
Dropped in?
Set a trap here
using this rock wall.
This alley
is a hard nut to crack.
Shinrokuro, what do you see?
Shinrokuro: Looks like
an ordinary boarding town.
Kuranaga:
lt is.
So we'll transform it
into a town of death.
Mitsuhashi,
get busy with the preparations.
Send lshizuka to keep watch.
- Koyata: Upashi.
Miss home?
l miss Upashi.
ls she that fine?
Like no woman
you've ever seen.
Soon, this quiet town
will become a bloodbath.
Go home alive while you can.
l got no home.
This is our fight.
You're not a samurai.
Don't trifle with your life.
Got it?
Damn samurai!
You and your honor
and causes!
l'll show you!
Vanished?
Lord Naritsugu passed through
Komagane along the lna road.
Then he vanished.
Back to Edo?
Not possible
with Naritsugu in control.
l'm concerned he'll cut through
to the Sanshu road and skip lida.
Without visiting the Naegi clan?
Shinzaemon:
Stand down.
Now, the playing field is level.
Hanbei is trying to ascertain
our next move.
We wait here.
Prepare for battle.
Batten down that side.
Yes! Put it there.
Shinzaemon: If they don't show today,
they must have gone to Okazaki.
Kuranaga:
Another route?
Mitsuhashi:
Waiting is killing our chances.
Let's abandon Ochiai tonight.
We can cross the pass
to the Sanshu Road.
Shinzaemon, it's time to decide!
- Too soon.
- But...
Do you know
the secret to fishing?
Wait until the fish
swallows the hook.
Reel it in when it swallows.
lt's simple.
But if you reel in too soon,
the fish will escape with the bait.
So you say
the Akashi are close?
With Hanbei at Naritsugu's side,
there is a chance...
they might skip the Naegi.
Their numbers are not Iike ours.
Even if they went off the road...
70 men cannot travel
without being noticed.
They must be in one place,
awaiting our next move.
And if this is so?
They'll come
if they think it's safe.
Shinzaemon: We wait
untiI the fish swaIIows the hook.
( distant hoofbeats
rumbIing )
They're here!
They're coming!
The Akashi men are coming!
From where?
Along the Ohira road.
But there are not 70.
What?
Many more. Over 200!
Two hundred?
Hanbei! He bought time and summoned
troops from other areas!
Twelve men can never defeat 200.
So what! As for the fish that takes
the hook, the bigger, the better.
Heaven's will brought us
all together.
Thirteen.
The time has come to lay down
your lives for the greater cause.
Are you ready?
Ready to die?
All:
Yes!
Shinzaemon:
Take your posts!
Hanbei:
Halt!
Asakawa, wait here.
Let me through.
Move out!
Naritsugu: How much longer
to Nakatsugawa?
Tell me how far!
Naritsugu:
What's the matter?
Hanbei:
Oh no!
- My Lord!
Turn back! My Lord!
What fun.
l'm going in, Hanbei!
My Lord! Follow him!
lshizuka:
Hey!
You can get past this way.
This way, this way.
Shinzaemon.
l presume you are the Akashi entourage
of Lord Naritsugu.
By the order of His Shogun's subject,
Shinzaemon...
we commemorate your passage
with arrows!
Hanbei:
My Lord!
Leave the horses.
Protect our Lord.
My Lord.
Come this way.
Please wait.
Secure the interior.
- Huh?
- Secure the interior.
Hey, secure the interior.
Enough petty tricks.
Only 130 left!
What you paid for my life...
was a real bargain.
The enemy is not large!
Don't panic.
Show them the spirit
of Akashi samurai!
Trade your lives
to protect our Lord.
My Lord!
Lord!
TOTAL MASSACRE
Kill! Kill them all!
Ogura!
Samurai:
Fire? No, no!
My Lord!
l found a way out!
No! lt's a trap.
My Lord.
Come!
Hioki!
Guide:
Go, go!
This way, my Lord.
Look.
Ogura, kill the men
that get past me.
Don't leave one alive.
Yes, master.
Kill!
Hirayama:
Retreat.
Ogura!
Koyata: Your samurai brawls
are crazy fun.
lshizuka:
lt's no brawl!
Why are you samurai
so arrogant?
Why are you samurai...
Higuchi, you okay?
Thanks.
Hioki!
Hioki...
you fought well.
A true samurai.
Shinzaemon.
Higuchi!
- Go!
- Finish the job.
- Otake: lshizuka!
lshizuka!
Otake.
Our mission...
finish it!
Shinzaemon!
Mitsuhashi!
Damn!
You fool!
- Hanbei.
You think the age of war
was like this?
Perhaps.
lt's magnificent.
With death
comes gratitude for life.
lf a man has lived in vain,
then how trivial his life is.
Oh, Hanbei.
Something wonderful
has come to my mind.
Once l'm
on the Shogun's council,
let's bring back the age of war.
l'm Saheita Kuranaga.
Lord Naritsugu...
l've come for your life.
Sir Hanbei...
protect our Lord.
Comrade:
Kuranaga!
My Lord!
Master...
Who are you?
You're no samurai!
So what?
Do only samurai matter
in this world?
l thought
samurai would be fun...
but you bore me.
You're useless,
even more useless in great numbers.
This man speaks the truth.
His reward is my short sword.
lf we can get past that...
Remain focused.
Victory is ours!
Keep our Lord safe.
We'll win!
My Lord!
Let's run.
Hanbei,
victory is not yet ours.
Shinza.
Hanbei, l have no qualms
with you.
You will not pass.
l'll trade my life
to protect my Lord.
l must do
what must be done.
Are you so hungry
for my Lord's life?
Yes!
l gambled my life in this senseless war
of power and politics.
lf he joins the Shogun's council...
you know disaster
will befall the people!
- Am l wrong?
- So what then?
Both you and l
were born samurai.
Ours is not to wonder why.
Ours is...
to obey our fate and die.
Shinzaemon:
If you were my ally...
if you were not
an Akashi retainer...
wouIdn't our task be easier?
Don't lecture me!
No matter how low l go,
Hanbei Kito is a samurai!
l won't hand over
my Lord's head so easily.
Shinza...
to pass,
you'll have to kill me.
That l shall do.
Fight!
Such elegance in fighting
one-on-one.
How l missed
crossing swords with you!
Hanbei...
in the dojo,
we were an even match.
Hanbei...
see you in hell!
Some call it elegance.
Some call it cruel and unfair.
l like it.
How can you kick his head?
He gave his life for you!
Kick my head if you want.
For the Shogun, for the people,
for the many who died untimely deaths...
for Uneme Makino and his wife...
for his father, Yukie Makino...
and for my men scattering Ochiai.
For that...
innocent, nameless young girl...
with severed arms and legs...
l shall take your life!
Ruling is convenient...
but only for rulers.
The people must live to serve.
Even so, a time comes when servants
rise up against their Lords.
You're on top
thanks to support from the bottom.
Shinzaemon:
Don't you see?
Your mistake is believing
that your decorative blade
is not just for show.
Nonsense.
lt's not for show!
Decoration is for show.
Be silent
like the decorative man you are.
Servant!
How is this for show?
Uncle!
Pain.
lt hurts!
That's unexpected.
Can you feel pain?
Am l dying?
Dying?
l'm scared. So scared.
Scared.
l don't want...
to die.
l'm scared! l'm scared!
My Lord...
prepare yourself!
So death comes for us all.
Allow me to thank you,
Shinzaemon.
Of all the days of my life,
today has been
the most exciting.
You're welcome!
Shinzaemon:
It's over.
The big gamble paid off.
Shinrokuro...
being a samurai...
is truly a burden.
Do what you want...
with your life.
Shinrokuro:
Are you immortal?
You got the Lord's head
without me?
Our fight is over.
That ain't no fun.
- You hurt?
- Hmm? Oh...
Compared to fighting a wild bear,
these wounds are nothing.
All in all...
l want my Upashi.
l don't like towns
swarming with samurai.
l'll go home,
sweep Upashi off her feet...
and live far away!
Live your life.
Till the next life!
What are you going to do?
Whatever l want.
Been a samurai long enough.
Become a bandit.
The greatest bandit in Japan.
Jump ship to America,
make love to women.
Now you're talking.
Say "hi" to Upashi for me.
Sure.
( wood cracks,
horse whinnies )
ln May 1844,
it was reported
to the Central Government...
that Lord Naritsugu
fell ill and died.
Some 23 years later,
the Shogunate system was abolished.
The modern Meiji era began.
Koji Yakusho
Takayuki Yamada
Yusuke lseya
lkki Sawamura
Arata Furuta
Sousuke Takaoka
Seiji Rokkaku
lkki Namioka
Koen Kondo
Yuma lshigaki
Masataka Kubota
Tsuyoshi lhara
Hiroki Matsukata
Kazue Fukiishi - Mitsuki Tanimura
Takumi Saito - Shinnosuke Abe
Masaaki Uchino
Ken Mitsuishi
lttoku Kishibe
Mikijiro Hira
Koshiro Matsumoto
Goro lnagaki
Masachika lchimura
Directed by
Takashi Miike
Subtitles by Christian Storms